Welcome to Jupyter Lab and welcome to our experiments at the frontier.
개척지 실험에 오신 걸 환영해요
So we are going to put our frontier models to the test, trying out this challenge of predicting the
그래서 새로운 모델을 시험해 보려고 합니다 GPT 4와
prices of products using a combination of GPT four and Claude.
클로드를 조합해서 제품 가격을 예측하는 거죠
Uh, and I do want to point out a couple of things about this.
이와 관련해 몇 가지 지적하고 싶어요
First of all, it's worth pointing out that we're not doing any training here.
우선, 이건 훈련이 아니란 걸 강조해야 해요
We're not going to give the frontier models any benefit of the training data.
개척지 모델에는 훈련 데이터의 혜택을 주지 않을 거예요
We're simply going to be giving it the test data and asking it to predict the outcome.
테스트 데이터를 주고 결과를 예측하도록 요청할 뿐이죠
So when we looked at traditional machine learning, we gave it the 400,000 training data points and
전통적인 머신 러닝을 살펴볼 때 400,000개의 훈련 데이터 포인트를 주고
had it learn a model based on that.
그걸 기반으로 모델을 배우게 했어요
In this case, we're simply giving it the test data and saying, given all of your phenomenal knowledge
이 경우에는 테스트 데이터를 주는 거죠 세상에 대해 알고 있는 경이로운
of of everything that you know about the world, all of the world information stored in your trillions
모든 지식 수조 개의 매개 변수에 저장된 모든 정보를 가지고
of parameters, please predict the price of this product and do it by finishing this the sentence this
제품의 가격을 예측해 보세요 그리고 이 문장을 끝내세요 이 제품은
product is worth dollars, and then the model is convinced that the most likely next token is going
달러 가치가 있다 그러면 모델은 가장 그럴듯한 다음 토큰이 그 제품의 가격이 될 것이라고
to be a plausible price for that product.
확신하죠
So we're taking advantage of its world knowledge.
그래서 그 세계의 지식을 이용하는 거죠
So yeah, on the one hand it's not been trained for this task.
한편으로는 이 작업에 대한 훈련을 받지 않았어요
Uh, on the other hand though, something else that's worth mentioning that maybe some of you thought
한편으로는 이미 생각하셨을지 모르지만 언급할
already is that given the enormous, outrageously large training data set that has been put through
만한 다른 주제가 있습니다. 훈련의 일환으로 이런 모델로 만들어진 어마어마하게 방대한
these models as part of training, it's entirely possible that they have, in fact, seen these products
훈련 데이터셋을 보면 이런 제품들을 이미 봤을 가능성이 충분히 있다는 거죠.
They may have been provided with scrapes of Amazon.
아마존에서 가져온 걸 수도 있죠
They may have been provided with hugging face data sets, for all we know.
포옹하는 얼굴 데이터 세트를 제공했을지도 모르죠
Uh, so, um, it's possible now.
이제 가능하대요
Now they don't.
이젠 아니에요
You'll see that results aren't suspiciously spot on or something.
결과가 의심스러울 정도로 정확하진 않아요
That would make one feel that it has the benefit of precise prices, but we do still have to bear in
그렇다면 정확한 가격의 혜택을 누릴 수 있겠지만 부당한 이점이 있을 수
mind that it might have an unfair advantage.
있다는 걸 명심해야 해요
I haven't seen evidence of that, but it's certainly something that one wants to be worried about.
그런 증거는 못 봤지만 확실히 걱정해야 할 문제인 건 분명해요
It's what people call testata contamination.
테스타타 오염이라고 하죠
When there's a possibility that your test data set has been seen, or has aspects of it have been seen
테스트 데이터가 목격되거나 훈련 중에 그 측면이 보였을 가능성이
during training time.
있을 때요
So we'll bear that in mind.
그걸 명심하세요
But that's just going to be a side note.
그건 여담으로 남겨둘게요
We're not going to dwell more on that.
그 얘기는 그만하죠
I haven't seen significant evidence that that is at play.
그게 관련됐다는 중요한 증거는 못 봤어요
So we're going to do some imports.
수입 작업을 할 거예요
There they go.
저기 가네요
We are now back to importing OpenAI and anthropic and we'll be making use of them.
오픈AI와 인류애를 다시 수입하고 있어요 그걸 활용할 거예요
Now you remember I wrote that lovely tester class that I do like, and I think it's going to be very
제가 만든 테스터 수업 기억하시죠? 제가 좋아하는 건데 여러분께 아주 유용할
useful for you.
거예요
And I encourage you to be writing similar kinds of test harness frameworks for your own projects to
가능한 많은 비즈니스 지표를 사용해 결과를 검증하기 위한 여러분의 프로젝트를
validate their results using the using as many business metrics as you can.
위해 유사한 테스트 하니스 프레임워크를 작성하시길 권장해요
I've moved it out into a separate, uh, Python module of its own.
파이썬 을 가지고 있는 분리된 모듈로 옮겼어요
This is the same code that's out in a module like that, and that just means that we don't have to have
이런 모듈에 있는 것과 같은 코드예요 그 말은 Jupyter 노트북에 이게
it in all of our Jupyter notebooks going forwards, because we will use it quite a lot.
있을 필요가 없다는 거죠 앞으로 꽤 많이 사용할 테니까요
We can just import it like so, and it will be there.
이렇게 불러오기만 하면 돼요
And the the signature has changed very slightly.
서명이 아주 약간 바뀌었어요
We'll have to say Tesla dot test, put in the function name and also pass in the test data set, of
테슬라 put test라고 적고 함수 이름을 넣고 시험 데이터 세트에도 통과시켜야
which it will take the first 250 elements data points.
해요 250개의 요소 데이터 포인트를 취할 거예요
All right.
좋아요
So with that we are now going to load in our environment variables.
이제 환경 변수를 로드할 거예요
We are going to log in to hugging face.
얼굴 포옹에 로그인할게요
Uh again I don't think we're actually going to use that.
다시 말씀드리지만 그건 안 쓸 것 같아요
But um anyway might as well we get into the practice of it.
어쨌든 get it의 실천을 시작해 보죠.
Uh, always nice to log into hugging face, isn't it?
포옹하는 얼굴 로그인하면 늘 좋죠
We will initialize our two models.
두 모델을 초기화할 거예요
We will, uh, tell matplotlib that we are going to be making charts, and we will load in our pickle
Mattplotlib에 우리가 차트를 만들 거라고 말할 거예요. 그리고 우리가 출력한
files for our training and test data set that we outputted.
트레이닝과 테스트 데이터 세트를 위해 피클 파일을 로드할 거예요.
Um, and they are loaded in.
장전도 됐고요
Now, I did say we were just about to go straight to the frontier, but I am going to, uh, pause for
개척지로 곧장 간다고 말씀드렸지만 잠시 멈춰 보겠습니다 개척지로
one more second, because I do have one other model to show you before we go to the frontier.
가기 전에 보여 드릴 모델이 하나 더 있거든요
And you're thinking, oh, come on, you said it was frontier time, but I think you will be amused
서구 시대라고 하셨지만 이것도 재미있을 거예요
And this came very much at my expense.
제가 그 대가를 치렀죠
And this is why, at the start of today's videos, I said I was absolutely exhausted.
그래서 오늘 영상을 시작할 때 너무 피곤하다고 한 거예요
But it did occur to me that another, perhaps another thing that we should compare our models to would
하지만 우리 모델을 비교해 봐야 할 또 다른 대상은 제품 가격을 예측하려는
be the efforts of humanity in trying to predict prices of products.
인류의 노력일 거라는 생각이 들었죠
It seems like we should have that baseline as well, so that we can compare our model performance against
기준선도 있어야 할 것 같습니다 모델의 성능과 인간의 성능을
human performance.
비교할 수 있게요
And I couldn't find anybody that I could convince to go through the horror that is reading 250 product
250개의 제품 설명을 읽고 가격을 계산하는 등의 공포를 감당할 수 있는 사람을
descriptions and trying to figure out how much they cost.
찾을 수가 없었어요
And so I subjected myself to this torture and torture it was.
그래서 스스로를 고문했어요 정말 고문이 따로 없었죠
I can tell you it is way more difficult than I was expecting.
제가 예상했던 것보다 훨씬 어렵네요
I said to you before that I thought it was it was quite hard, but it's way harder than I had realized
전에 꽤 힘들 거라고 말씀드렸는데 생각했던 것보다 훨씬 힘들어요
there are just things that I had no idea about.
제가 전혀 몰랐던 것들이 있어요
I had no idea how much it costs to buy a wheel, and there are a couple of wheels in there.
바퀴 하나에 얼마인지 몰랐는데 바퀴가 몇 개 있네요
Uh, then, even though I should know computers back to front, I found myself agonizing over the cost
컴퓨터의 순서를 알아야 하는데도 복원한 컴퓨터의 디스크
of refurbished computers with 400GB of, uh, disk space.
공간이 400GB나 돼서 고민하게 되더라고요
And, yeah, it was just really, really hard.
네, 정말 힘들었어요
And chandeliers.
샹들리에도요
I don't know how much a chandelier costs.
샹들리에가 얼마인지 모르겠어요
Anyway, I digress.
본론에서 벗어났네요
I wrote some code that outputs to a CSV file 250 test prompts, and after I ran that, uh, I'll run
코드를 작성해서 CSV파일 250 테스트 프롬프트에 출력합니다. 이것을 실행한 후에는, 실행해 볼게요.
it.
이제 파일을 생성합니다 사람 입력 .csv
And here is human input dot CSV.
여기 사람 입력 .CSV가 있네요
And it contains the prompts every single one of the top 250 prompts and zero in this column to be filled
프롬프트들을 포함하고 있습니다 상위 250개의 프롬프트들 전부를요 이 칼럼에 0은
in by said human.
사람이 채울 수 있죠
Uh, and I, you know, I'm not even sure if I'm going to check in this human output into into git.
이 사람 산출물을 깃에 체크해야 할지조차 모르겠어요
If you see it there, then I then I've dared to because I after a while you become fatigued and I was
보시면 아시겠지만 제가 감히 했어요 시간이 좀 지나면 지치거든요 너무
going through it probably too fast.
빨리 진행한 것 같아요
I probably made some real blunders in there.
제가 큰 실수를 한 것 같아요
If you look at it, you'll probably say, what were you thinking?
무슨 생각으로 그랬는지 궁금하실 거예요
You should stick to teaching LM engineering.
당신은 LM 엔지니어링이나 가르쳐요
Certainly don't.
당연히 아니죠
You're not, not not someone of the world.
당신은 이 세상의 사람이 아니에요
Uh, but, um, yeah, I gave it my best shot.
하지만 최선을 다하긴 했어요
So anyways, we'll read back in the prices that I set.
제가 정한 가격을 다시 읽어볼게요
Uh, and then let's just, uh, quickly get a sense for, for, for how this looks.
Get it가 어떻게 보일지 간단히 짚어 보죠
So we're going to write a function which is going to be the human, um, the predictor, the human processor.
그래서 우리가 쓸 함수는 인간 예측기인 인간 프로세서예요
So it needs to take an input.
그래서 입력이 필요하죠
And that input should be one of the items.
그 입력이 항목 중 하나가 되어야 해요
And its job is to return the cost of that item.
그 물건의 가격을 환불하는 게 그 기계의 일이죠
Um, so what I do at this point is I say, okay, so if I look in my training data set, I say my test
음, 이 시점에서 제가 하는 것은, 트레이닝 데이터 세트를 보면 테스트 데이터 세트라고
data set.
하죠
What is the index of that item?
그 항목의 인덱스는 뭐죠?
So is it the the zeroth item in in test.
테스트의 0번째 항목인가요?
Is it the first the second the third.
첫 번째인가요? 두 번째인가요? 세 번째인가요?
And we will call that index.
그걸 인덱스라고 부르죠
So that is which number of the test items we are looking at here.
여기서 보고 있는 테스트 아이템의 개수죠
And then I have read in all of my hopeless estimates into human predictions.
그리고 가망 없는 예측을 전부 읽었어요
And so we will simply return human predictions.
그래서 인간의 예측을 다시 보여드리려고 해요
At uh at index.
인덱스 에서도요
All right.
좋아요
And run that.
실행하세요
And now now we will see we will see tester dot test human pricer.
이제 테스터가 인간 프라이서를 테스트할 거예요
And pass in the test data set.
테스트 데이터 세트도 통과시키고요
Here we go.
시작할게요
So there are the results.
결과가 나왔네요
Uh, well you can see that there's a fairly large number of reds in there.
붉은 연어가 꽤 많이 보여요
There are some greens though.
그래도 녹색은 좀 있네요
I did respectably.
정중하게 했어요
Uh, but still I was quite far out.
그래도 꽤 멀리까지 갔어요
But look, this one.
하지만 이걸 보세요
What is this?
이게 뭐죠?
Richmond auto upholstery, I guess 260.
리치먼드 자동차 덮개 전문점 260점 정도 될 거예요
And it was 225.
225달러였어요
And this one here, Gibson Performance exhaust.
이건 깁슨 퍼포먼스 배기관이에요
I don't know how much a Gibson Performance exhaust costs, but I.
깁슨 퍼포먼스 배기관이 얼마인지는 모르지만요
I guessed 499.
499개라고 생각했어요
I thought I'd, you know, go go for it.
그래서 한번 해 보기로 했죠
And the answer is 535.
답은 535예요
But then some others in here.
하지만 다른 사람들도 있어요
What did I get wrong here?
Get it, get it, get it, get it! 내가 뭘 잘못 알고 있는 거죠?
A Street Series stainless performance something, uh, I guess $260 and it was $814, so I was just
Street Series Senless 성능인가 뭔가였는데 260달러쯤 했어요 814달러였죠
way off there anyway to put me out of my misery.
어쨌든 너무 빗나갔어요 고통을 덜어주려고요
If we scroll down, we will see.
스크롤을 내리면 보일 거예요
Here is the chart then, uh, I uh, in particular, you'll see that I didn't do terribly.
여기 차트가 있어요 제가 형편없지 않다는 걸 보실 수 있죠
I mean, I did.
아니, 그랬다고요
All right, look, lots of green dots hit rate of 32%.
보세요, 많은 녹색 점이 32%에 도달해요
Um, I, I also I realized actually, as I was About two thirds of the way through that, all of my
그리고 3분의 2 정도 봤을 때 제가 생각한 가격은 400-500달러
prices, I'd never guessed anything much more than 4 or $500.
정도였어요
So I knew immediately that obviously I was.
그래서 제가 그런다는 걸 바로 알았죠
I hadn't I hadn't spotted things that were expensive.
비싼 건 못 봤어요
So that was obviously a failing.
그건 명백한 실패였죠
Um, so my total error, as it happens, was $127.
제 총 오류는 127달러였어요
And that means I come in better than than than the average.
평균보다 더 잘한다는 뜻이죠
It's not like I could have done better just by guessing the average number all the way through.
처음부터 끝까지 맞힌다고 더 잘 만들 수 있는 것도 아니고요
Uh, the, uh, I've written down to remind myself the the comparisons.
비교를 위해 적어 봤어요
The average was 146.
평균은 146점이었어요
Uh, was the error of the average price.
평균 가격의 오류였어요
So I did better than that.
그보다는 잘했죠
The straight up linear regression with feature engineering.
기능 엔지니어링의 선형 회귀죠
The basic one was 139.
기본은 139개였어요
So I beat that.
그래서 이겼어요
I beat a very, very basic feature engineering linear regression.
아주 기본적인 기능 공학 선형 회귀를 깼어요
But you probably already put in more features and did better than that anyway.
하지만 이미 더 많은 기능을 넣고 그것보다 잘했을 거예요.
Um, but then all of the other models are crushed me with the, the bag of words style models and the
그런데 다른 모델들이 전부 단어의 봉지에 담긴 스타일과 두 개의 벡 모델로 저를 압도했어요
And then you remember that Random Forest came in at 97, significantly better than humanity.
랜덤 포레스트는 97년에 등장했는데 인류보다 훨씬 뛰어났죠
So already as it would happen, good traditional machine learning models can do better than this human
기존의 좋은 머신 러닝 모델은 사람보다 제품 가격 예측에 더 뛰어납니다
anyway in predicting the prices of items, but you may be better informed than me if you put yourself
하지만 직접 해 보면 저보다 더 잘 알 거예요 추천하진 않아요
through this exercise, which I do not recommend.
TUI
Then you may find you may find that you do better.
더 잘 살 수 있다는 걸 알게 될 거예요
Anyway, in all seriousness, I haven't just wasted your time.
어쨌든, 제가 여러분의 시간을 낭비한 건 아니에요
This is the kind of exercise that's good to do because maybe for a few data points, but it gives you
이런 운동은 도움이 됩니다 데이터 포인트를 몇 개 얻을 수도 있지만
a good sense of the type of problem you're solving, and where the bar is set in terms of human performance
어떤 문제를 해결하는지 감이 올 수 있거든요 인적 능력이라는 기준점이 어디에 있는지
is something which can be used to compare how well we're doing with models.
모델로 얼마나 잘하는지 비교할 수 있으니까요
After all, if we can't do better than then, than the human performance, then we need to work harder.
결국 사람보다 더 잘할 수 없다면 더 열심히 노력해야죠
So that gives you a sense.
그걸 보면 감이 오죠
And when we come back in the next video, we really will move on to Frontier Models.
다음 비디오에서는 개척 시대 모델에 대해 얘기해 보죠
It's happening.
시작됐어요
See you then.
그때 봐요